torispelling.com 2013-12-07

# privacy | ediTORIal by Tori Spelling

This Policy was last changed on February 14, 2013

Everyday Health Media, LLC d/b/a EQAL Media and its affiliates ("Everyday Health," “us” or “we”) operate this website (the "Site"), and other websites that are part of the Everyday Health portfolio of websites (collectively, the "Sites") and the services related to or offered on the Sites (hereinafter, the "Services"). Some of the Sites are websites that we operate on behalf of third party licensors, for example, [ToriSpelling.com](https://torispelling.com/) (collectively, "Licensors"). Everyday Health's Services may include, without limitation, tools, applications, email services, bulletin and message boards, chat areas, news groups, forums, communities, calendars, and downloadable mobile applications related to the Sites or provided through the Sites.

We provide you this privacy policy (the "Policy") to help you understand the kinds of information we may gather about you when you visit the Site or use any of our Services, how we may use and disclose the information, and how you can control, correct and/or update the information.

To be clear about the terminology we are using, when we use the phrase "Personal Information" in this Policy, we mean information that can be used to identify or contact a person, like a person’s full name, address, e-mail address, or phone number. When we use the phrase "Anonymous Information" in this Policy, we mean information that cannot reasonably be used to identify individual persons.

By visiting this Site or using the Services, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Policy. Each time you visit the Site or use the Services, you agree and expressly consent to our collection, use and disclosure of the information that you provide as described in this Policy.

Your Personal Information will be processed by us in the United States.

In addition to this general Policy, each Service may have additional privacy provisions that are specific to the particular Service. These supplemental disclosures are made adjacent to the particular Service at the time we collect the information. These supplemental disclosures also govern the use of your information.

## 1\. The Information We Gather

We collect information about you in the following ways:

**A. Information you voluntarily provide us**

We collect and maintain information that you voluntarily submit to us during your use of the Sites and Services. For example:

  * when you register for a Site, you may provide us certain information including your name, email address, screen name, password, demographic information and the health topics that interest you;
  * to engage a Site's social networking function, you may add to your profile by providing information about your interests or health topics. For example, your profile may list your favorite healthy foods or movie;
  * if you are registering for a customized weight loss program, you may provide us answers to questions we use to provide you the program, like your actual and goal weights, your preferred method of exercise, or your caloric intake;
  * if you sign up to receive a newsletter, enter a contest or participate in social networking activities, you may provide us contact information (e.g., email or physical address);
  * if you purchase a product or service, you may provide us your credit card information; and
  * you may provide us with Personal Information in the course of email, customer support interactions and surveys.

You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but this may stop you from gaining access to a Service or limit the features that you can use. For more information, please see the **How We Use Your Information** section below.

**B. Information we collect through your use of the Site.**

As you use the Site and Services, certain information may also be passively collected. Through cookies, pixels, beacons, log files and other technologies, we may collect information about how you use the Site and the Services. For example we may determine through an IP address that a particular computer or device is located in New York City and we may use this information to deliver advertisements promoting New York City-based businesses. This information allows us to deliver more helpful information, programs, tools and advertisements. Please see the **Cookies and Targeted Advertising** sections below for more information.

**C. Information we receive from third parties.**

We may also combine online and/or offline information received from third parties with the information we have already collected from you via our Sites and Services. The third party information is used for a variety of purposes including to verify other information about you (e.g., verify your mailing address to send you requested products or services) and to enhance the content and advertising we provide to you.

## 2\. How We Use Your Information

We will use your Personal Information in the ways described below or described at the time that the information is collected.

**A. Advertising.**

We believe that advertising is more interesting to you when it is relevant. Accordingly, we customize the advertisements that you see based upon: (i) the information that you provide us; (ii) geographic location information, which we may determine through your IP address, from your mobile device, or other ways; (iii) data we receive from third parties or; (iv) your visits on the Sites or use of Services (commonly referred to as "Behavioral Advertising"). Please see the **Cookies and Targeted Advertising** section below for more information on the use of cookies and the information collected for Behavioral Advertising.

You can limit the way that we tailor advertising based on your self-reported interests and other information in your profile by visiting the “Edit Profile” section of the Member Profile Page of the Site and deleting or modifying the information. Please see the section below on Updating and Control of Your Personal Information for more information. Please note that if you have registered on multiple Sites, you'll need to modify your profile on each Site. In addition, you can delete the cookies that we have placed on your browser. Please see the section below on **Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Address Information** for more information.

**B. To Provide the Sites and Services.**

In general, we use your Personal Information as necessary or appropriate for purposes including to:

  * administer your account;
  * register you and provide you access to the Site or Services;
  * respond to inquiries or requests that you direct to us;
  * fulfill your requests for products or services;
  * send communications and administrative emails about the Sites or Services;
  * personalize and better tailor the features, performance and support of the Sites and Services for your use;
  * send you promotional/marketing information, newsletters, offers or other information regarding opportunities and functionality that we think would be of particular interest to you;
  * improve the quality of the Site and the Services, and
  * analyze, benchmark and conduct research on user data and user interactions with the Site and Services.

## 3\. Cookies and Targeted Advertising

**A. Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Address Information**

  * "Cookies" are small pieces of information that a website places on your browser when you visit that website. We may use cookies to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience with the Sites and Services. For example, we may use cookies to control what advertisements you see, the sequence of advertisements and to make sure you don't see the same advertisement too many times. For contests or sweepstakes, we may also use cookies in order to track your progress and the number of entries in some promotions. For polls, we may use cookies to help ensure that an individual can't vote more than once on a particular question or issue. We do not store Personal Information in any cookies on your computer.
  * Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser's directions within the help tab. In order to use certain Services offered through the Sites, your web browser must accept cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, some aspects of the Sites may not work properly, and you may not be able to access our Services.
  * We may also use cookies, pixels, web beacons (which are usually small, transparent graphic images), operating system and device information and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit, the features and information for which you searched and viewed, the email you opened, or on which advertisements you clicked. This type of information is collected to make the Sites and Services more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs.
  * An "Internet protocol address" or "IP Address" is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We, or our service providers, may use your IP Address when you access the Sites or Services or use other means to assist with delivering geographically targeted advertisements.

**B. Targeted Advertising**

Companies Everyday Health works with may use cookies for purposes including understanding Web usage patterns of users who see advertisements on the Sites, controlling the sequence of advertisements you see, making sure you don't see the same advertisement too many times, determining your interests and tailoring advertisements and promotions based on those interests. For example, if you read an article on one of the Sites, we may use cookies from a vendor to later serve you an advertisement for a product related to the viewed article. These third party vendors may connect information about pages you visit on our Sites with information about pages you visit on other websites and show you advertising based on this combined information. The advertisement may appear when you are visiting a different section of this Site, another Site or any other website on the Internet if the website also has a relationship with our vendor. You can choose to limit Behavioral Advertising on the Sites by clicking [**here**](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and opting-out of cookies placed by those vendors listed. After you opt-out, you will still see advertisements but the advertising may not be as relevant to your interests. If you change your computer, change your browser, or delete your cookies, you will need to renew your opt-out.

We adhere to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising of the Digital Advertising Alliance (for more information click [**here**](http://www.aboutads.info/consumers)).

**C. Information Collected by Third Party Advertisers**

Advertisers or other third parties on the Sites may also engage in Behavioral Advertising and use cookies and web beacons in the manner described above. We do not control these advertisers or other parties' use of cookies or web beacons or what they do with the information they collect. Many third party vendors that engage in Behavioral Advertising participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) and abide by NAI and/or DAA principles. If you wish to opt out of participating in advertising programs conducted by NAI and DAA members or learn more about the NAI and DAA, please go to the [**NAI Opt-Out**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) website and [**DAA Choice Page**](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) and follow the instructions. After you opt-out, you will still see advertisements, but the advertising may not be as relevant to your interests. If you change your computer, change your browser or delete your cookies, you will need to renew your opt-out.

## 4\. How We Disclose Information to Third Parties

We may share your Personal Information with third parties as specifically approved by you or under the circumstances described below. If you do not want us to use or disclose Personal Information collected about you in the ways identified in this Policy, you should not use the Site or Services.

**A. Disclosure for legal reasons.**

We may disclose and release your Personal Information to third parties: (a) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (b) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others, a threat to homeland security, a threat to our system or network, or in any cases in which we believe it is reasonably necessary to investigate or prevent harm, fraud, abuse, illegal conduct or a violation or alleged violation of this Policy or other agreement we may have with you.

**B. Agents and Contractors.**

We may provide your Personal Information to service providers who work on our behalf or help us to operate our business, the Sites and the Services. Examples of such service providers include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content for sending email, analyzing data, research, providing advertising and marketing assistance, processing payments (including credit card payments), and providing customer service. Access to your Personal Information by these service providers is limited to the information reasonably necessary to perform its limited function.

**C. Aggregated, Anonymous Information.**

We may share aggregated Anonymous Information about you with third parties. Aggregated information is your Anonymous Information that is combined with the Anonymous Information of other users.

**D. Contests, sweepstakes and polls.**

Some or all of the information collected during a promotions, contest, polls, or sweepstakes (“Promotions”) may be disclosed publicly. It may also be shared with other third parties as disclosed at the time of collection or in the Promotion rules. These third parties may include providers of prizes in order to update you of your status of your prize or other fulfillment needs or a co-sponsor who may use your Personal Information to administer the Promotion or for their marketing purposes, but only in conformance with their privacy policy as made available to you at the time of collection. Everyday Health is not responsible for their privacy policy or practices.

When you participate in a Promotion, you are subject to any official rules for that Promotion, which may contain additional information about the specific privacy practices associated with the Promotion.

**E. Licensors.**

Some of the Sites are websites that Everyday Health operates on behalf of Licensors, for example LaurenConrad.com. Everyday Health may share some or all of your Personal Information with its Licensors. This Policy does not cover the use of your Personal Information by Licensors. The privacy practices of Everyday Health's Licensors may differ from this policy and we encourage you to contact those third parties directly if you have questions regarding their use of your Personal Information.

**F. Sponsors, Merchants and other ways that you approve at the time of collection.**

We may collect Personal Information about you and share it with third parties to the extent that you give us permission at the time of collection. For example, if you purchase a deal or service, we will provide your information to the applicable merchant or vendor. We also sometimes gather Personal Information on behalf of a sponsor in association with a promotion. In such a case, we will provide you notice at the time of collection that the information is being collected on the sponsor's behalf and link to the sponsor's privacy policy.

**G. Within our Company; Changes to our Company.**

We may share your Personal Information with any of our subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control. Additionally, in the event we go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information may be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and are permitted by this Policy.

## 5\. Message Boards and Member Search

We may make message boards, chat rooms, and other interactive forums available as part of the Services. You should be aware that any information which you post to these interactive forums or otherwise choose to make publicly available, including your Personal Information, may be disclosed and available to all users who have access to that portion of the Site or Services. By using these interactive forums, you agree that we are not responsible for any information that you disclose or communicate in such forums, and any disclosures you make are at your own risk.

In order to locate other members of the Sites that you may already know in the physical world, we allows users to search for a member’s full name, email address or other Personal Information. We also allow users to browse for certain profile information in order to help connect with members. Users may also choose to publicly display some registration information via a profile setting under the "Edit Profile" section of the Sites. Search engines may index the portion of a member's profile (including the Personal Information it contains) that is publicly displayed.

## 6\. Children's Information

The Site and Services are not directed or intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from individuals under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age, you should not register or provide Personal Information on the Site or through the Services. If you are the parent or guardian of a child whom you believe has disclosed Personal Information to us, please contact us at privacy@everydayhealth.com so that we may delete and remove such child's information from our systems.

## 7\. Updating and Control of Your Personal Information

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Information. When you receive promotional communications from us you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the promotional e-mail or newsletter you receive or by editing your preference to receive these communications within the "Manage My Email" or similar feature on the individual Sites when you are logged in as a registered user.

If your Personal Information changes or if you no longer desire to display information on the Sites or Services, we encourage you to correct, update or remove Personal Information from your profile. This can be done by logging-in and clicking on your user name at top of the Site to access the "Profile" section. If you would like assistance disabling your account please contact customer service at [support@everydayhealth.com](mailto:support@everydayhealth.com) or call 1-888-795-4719.

Keep in mind, however, that even if you delete information from your profile, we may retain your Personal Information in conformance with our data retention policy and Personal Information may remain within our databases, access logs, and other records. In addition, we are not responsible for updating or removing your Personal Information contained in the lists or databases of third parties who have been provided information as permitted by this Policy.

## 8\. Co-branded Sections of the Sites

Certain portions of the Sites or certain Services may be co-branded with a business partner and subject to a different privacy policy that is either the partner's privacy policy or a privacy policy developed jointly by Everyday Health and our partner (collectively the "Co-branded Policy"). The partner's collection, use and dissemination practices regarding any data or Personal Information provided by, or obtained from users of these Co-branded portions of the Sites will be governed by the Co-branded Policy. Please read the Co-branded Policy for each Co-branded Site before providing any Personal Information.

## 9\. Third Party Links

The Sites may link to websites operated by third parties that we do not control. We do not monitor, control, or endorse the information collection or privacy practices of any third parties. We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of every website you visit and to contact them if you have any questions about their respective privacy policies and practices. This Policy applies solely to information collected by us through the Sites or Services and does not apply to these third party websites. The ability to access information of third parties from the Sites or Services, or links to other websites or locations, is for your convenience only and does not signify our endorsement of such third parties, their products, services, websites, locations or their content.

## 10\. Security

We place a priority on the security of Personal Information, and we undertake reasonable security measures to help protect the data that resides on our servers. We also use secure server software (SSL) to process all financial transactions that occur on the Site. SSL technology can encrypt Personal Information transmitted over the Internet. However, no security system is impenetrable. We do not warrant the security of our servers, nor do we warrant that your information, including Personal Information, will be completely secure or not be intercepted while being transmitted over the Internet.

## 11\. How To Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding privacy or this Policy, you may contact us as follows:

Telephone: 888-795-4719

Email: privacy@everydayhealth.com

Address: Everyday Health Media, LLC 345 Hudson Street, 16th Floor New York, NY 10014

## 12\. Privacy Policy Changes

We reserve the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time and without prior notice, and any changes will become effective immediately upon being posted unless we advise you otherwise. Your continued use of the Site or Services after this Policy has been amended shall be deemed to be your continued acceptance of the terms and conditions of the Policy, as amended. We encourage you to bookmark this Web page and review this Policy regularly.
